<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>User Access Node (UAN)</title>
    <link>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/</link>
    <description>Recent content on User Access Node (UAN)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 14:14:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/installation_prereqs/prepare_for_uan_product_installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 14:14:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/installation_prereqs/prepare_for_uan_product_installation/</guid>
      <description>Prepare for UAN Product Installation Perform this procedure to ready the HPE Cray EX supercomputer for UAN product installation.
Install and configure the COS product before performing this procedure.
Verify that the management network switches are properly configured.
Refer to the switch configuration procedures in the HPE Cray System Management Documentation.
Ensure that the management network switches have the proper firmware.
Refer to the procedure &amp;ldquo;Update the Management Network Firmware&amp;rdquo; in the HPE Cray EX hardware documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/installation_prereqs/configure_the_bmc_for_uans_with_ilo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 14:14:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/installation_prereqs/configure_the_bmc_for_uans_with_ilo/</guid>
      <description>Configure the BMC for UANs with iLO Perform this procedure to enable the IPMI/DCMI settings on an HPE UAN that are necessary to continue UAN product installation on an HPE Cray EX supercomputer.
Perform the first three steps of Prepare for UAN Product Installation before performing this procedure.
Create the SSH tunnel necessary to access the BMC web GUI interface.
Find the IP or hostname for a UAN.
Create an SSH tunnel to the UAN BMC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/installation_prereqs/configure_the_bios_of_an_hpe_uan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 14:14:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/installation_prereqs/configure_the_bios_of_an_hpe_uan/</guid>
      <description>Configure the BIOS of an HPE UAN Perform this procedure to configure the network interface and boot settings required by HPE UANs.
Before the UAN product can be installed on HPE UANs, specific network interface and boot settings must be configured in the BIOS.
Perform Configure the BMC for UANs with iLO before performing this procedure.
Force a UAN to reboot into the BIOS.
In the following command, UAN_BMC_XNAME is the xname of the BMC of the UAN to configure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/installation_prereqs/configure_the_bios_of_a_gigabyte_uan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 14:14:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/installation_prereqs/configure_the_bios_of_a_gigabyte_uan/</guid>
      <description>Configure the BIOS of a Gigabyte UAN Perform this procedure to configure the network interface and boot settings required by Gigabyte UANs.
Before the UAN product can be installed on Gigabyte UANs, specific network interface and boot settings must be configured in the BIOS.
Press the Delete key to enter the setup utility when prompted to do so in the console.
Navigate to the boot menu.
Set the Boot Option #1 field to Network:UEFI: PXE IP4 Intel(R) I350 Gigabit Network Connection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/operations/about_uan_configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 14:14:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/operations/about_uan_configuration/</guid>
      <description>About UAN Configuration This section describes the Ansible playbooks and roles that configure UANs.
UAN configuration overview Configuration of UAN nodes is performed by the Configuration Framework Service (CFS). CFS can apply configuration to both images and nodes. When the configuration is applied to nodes, the nodes must be booted and accessible through SSH over the Node Management Network (NMN).
The Ansible roles involved in UAN configuration are listed in the site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/operations/build_a_new_uan_image_using_the_cos_recipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 14:14:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/operations/build_a_new_uan_image_using_the_cos_recipe/</guid>
      <description>Build a New UAN Image Using a COS Recipe Prior to UAN 2.3, a similar copy of the COS recipe was imported with the UAN install. In the UAN 2.3 release, UAN does not install a recipe, and a COS recipe must be used. Additional uan packages will now be installed via CFS and the uan_packages role.
Perform the following before starting this procedure:
Install the COS, Slingshot, and UAN product streams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/operations/create_uan_boot_images/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 14:14:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/operations/create_uan_boot_images/</guid>
      <description>Create UAN Boot Images Perform Build a New UAN Image Using a COS Recipe before performing this procedure.
This procedure updates the configuration management git repository to match the installed version of the UAN product. That updated configuration is then used to create UAN boot images and a BOS session template.
UAN specific configuration, and other required configurations related to UANs are covered in this topic. Refer to product-specific documentation for further information on configuring other HPE products (for example, workload managers and the HPE Cray Programming Environment) that may be configured on the UANs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/operations/mount_a_new_file_system_on_an_uan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 14:14:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/operations/mount_a_new_file_system_on_an_uan/</guid>
      <description>Mount a New File System on a UAN Perform this procedure to create a mount point for a new file system on a UAN.
Perform Steps 1-9 of Create UAN Boot Images.
Create a directory for Application role nodes.
ncn-w001# mkdir -p group_vars/Application Define the home directory information for the new file system in the filesystems.yml file.
ncn-w001# vi group_vars/Application/filesystems.yml --- filesystems: - src: 10.252.1.1:/home mount_point: /home fstype: nfs4 opts: rw,noauto state: mounted Add the change from the working directory to the staging area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/operations/configure_interfaces_on_uans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 14:14:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/operations/configure_interfaces_on_uans/</guid>
      <description>Configure Interfaces on UANs Perform this procedure to configure network interfaces on UANs by editing a configuration file.
Interface configuration is performed by the uan_interfaces Ansible role. For details on the variables referred to in this procedure, see UAN Ansible Roles.
In the command examples of this procedure, PRODUCT_VERSION refers to the current installed version of the UAN product. Replace PRODUCT_VERSION with the UAN version number string when executing the commands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/operations/configure_pluggable_authentication_modules_pam_on_uans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 14:14:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/operations/configure_pluggable_authentication_modules_pam_on_uans/</guid>
      <description>Configure Pluggable Authentication Modules (PAM) on UANs Perform this procedure to configure PAM on UANs. This enables dynamic authentication support for system services.
Intialize and configure the Cray command line interface (CLI) tool on the system. See &amp;ldquo;Configure the Cray Command Line Interface (CLI)&amp;rdquo; in the CSM documentation for more information.
Verify that the Gitea Version Control Service (VCS) is running.
ncn-m001# kubectl get pods --all-namespaces | grep vcs services gitea-vcs-f57c54c4f-j8k4t 2/2 Running 1 11d services gitea-vcs-postgres-0 2/2 Running 0 11d Retrieve the initial Gitea login credentials for the crayvcs username.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/operations/uan_ansible_roles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 14:14:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/operations/uan_ansible_roles/</guid>
      <description>UAN Ansible Roles csm.gpg_keys The csm.gpg_keys role fetches the required GPG keys needed for HPE RPM verification.
uan_ca_cert The uan_ca_cert role installs a CA certificate on the system.
uan_disk_config The uan_disk_config role configures swap and scratch disk partitions on UAN nodes.
Requirements There must be disk devices found on the UAN node by the device_filter module or this role will exit with failure. This condition can be ignored by setting uan_require_disk to false.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/operations/boot_uans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 14:14:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/operations/boot_uans/</guid>
      <description>Boot UANs Perform this procedure to boot UANs using BOS so that they are ready for user logins.
Perform Create UAN Boot Images before performing this procedure.
Create a BOS session to boot the UAN nodes. Replace uan-sessiontemplate-PRODUCT_VERSION in the following command with the ID of the session template created by the initial UAN product installation or the UAN product upgrade process.
ncn-m001# cray bos session create --template-uuid uan-sessiontemplate-PRODUCT_VERSION --operation reboot --format json | tee session.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/operations/cve-2023-0461/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 14:14:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/operations/cve-2023-0461/</guid>
      <description>Mitigation for CVE-2023-0461 Description There is a use-after-free vulnerability in the Linux Kernel which can be exploited to achieve local privilege escalation. To reach the vulnerability kernel configuration flag CONFIG_TLS or CONFIG_XFRM_ESPINTCP has to be configured, but the operation does not require any privilege. There is a use-after-free bug of icsk_ulp_data of a struct inet_connection_sock. When CONFIG_TLS is enabled, user can install a tls context (struct tls_context) on a connected tcp socket.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/advanced/customizing_uan_images_manually/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 14:14:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/advanced/customizing_uan_images_manually/</guid>
      <description>Customizing UAN Images Manually Query IMS for the UAN Image you want to customize.
ncn-m001:~/ $ cray ims images list --format json | jq &amp;#39;.[] | select(.name | contains(&amp;#34;uan&amp;#34;))&amp;#39; { &amp;#34;created&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;2021-02-18T17:17:44.168655+00:00&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;id&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;6d46d601-c41f-444d-8b49-c9a2a55d3c21&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;link&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;etag&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;371b62c9f0263e4c8c70c8602ccd5158&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;path&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;s3://boot-images/6d46d601-c41f-444d-8b49-c9a2a55d3c21/manifest.json&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;type&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;s3&amp;#34; }, &amp;#34;name&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;uan-PRODUCT_VERSION-image&amp;#34; } Create a variable for the IMS image id in the returned data.
ncn-m001:~/ $ export IMS_IMAGE_ID=6d46d601-c41f-444d-8b49-c9a2a55d3c21 Using the IMS_IMAGE_ID, follow the instructions in the Customize an Image Root Using IMS in the CSM documentation to build the UAN Image.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/advanced/enabling_can_chn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 14:14:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/advanced/enabling_can_chn/</guid>
      <description>Enabling the Customer Access Network (CAN) or the Customer High Speed Network (CHN) The UAN product provides a role, uan_interfaces in the Configuration Framework Service (CFS). This role is suitable for Application type nodes, and in some circumstancs, configuring the CHN, on Compute type nodes.
Enable CAN or CHN by setting the following in the UAN CFS repo (the filename may be modified to whatever is appropriate):
ncn-m001:~/ $ cat group_vars/Application_UAN/can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/advanced/repurposing_compute_as_uan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 14:14:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/advanced/repurposing_compute_as_uan/</guid>
      <description>Repurposing a Compute Node as a UAN This section describes how to repurpose a compute node to be used as a User Access Node (UAN). This is typically done when the processor type of the compute node is not yet available in a UAN server.
Overview The following steps outline the process of repurposing a compute node to be used as a UAN.
Verify the System Default Route is set to CHN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/advanced/sles_image/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 14:14:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/advanced/sles_image/</guid>
      <description>Booting an Application Node with a SLES Image (Technical Preview) A SLES image is available for use with Application type nodes. This image is currently considered a &amp;ldquo;Technical Preview&amp;rdquo; as the initial support for booting with SLES Images without COS. This guide documents the procedure to boot and configure the new image as it currently differs from the standard COS-based image process in some ways.
The image is built with the same packer/qemu pipeline as Non-Compute-Node Images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/advanced/enabling_k3s/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 14:14:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/advanced/enabling_k3s/</guid>
      <description>Configuring a UAN for K3s (Technical Preview) WARNING: This feature is currently a Technical Preview, as such it requires completion of the Prerequisites section. Future releases will streamline these manual configuration steps and enhance the experience of using the rootless podman containers. Therefore, some of these configuration options may change in future releases.
UAI Experience on UANs In UAN 2.6, a new playbook has been added to create a single node, K3s cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/troubleshooting/troubleshoot_uan_boot_issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 14:14:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/troubleshooting/troubleshoot_uan_boot_issues/</guid>
      <description>Troubleshoot UAN Boot Issues The UAN boot process BOS boots UANs. BOS uses session templates to define various parameters such as:
Which nodes to boot Which image to boot Kernel parameters Whether to perform post-boot configuration (Node Personalization) of the nodes by CFS. Which CFS configuration to use if Node Personalization is enabled. UAN boots are performed in three phases:
PXE booting an iPXE binary that will load the initrd of the UAN image that will boot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/troubleshooting/troubleshoot_uan_cfs_and_network_configuration_issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 14:14:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/troubleshooting/troubleshoot_uan_cfs_and_network_configuration_issues/</guid>
      <description>Troubleshoot UAN CFS and Network Configuration Issues Examine the UAN CFS pod logs to help troubleshoot CFS and networking issues on UANs.
Read About UAN Configuration before starting this procedure.
Obtain the name of the CFS session that failed by running the following command on a management or worker NCN:
This example sorts the list of CFS sessions so that the most recent one is at the bottom.
ncn# kubectl -n services get pods --sort-by=.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/troubleshooting/troubleshoot_uan_disk_configuration_issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 14:14:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/troubleshooting/troubleshoot_uan_disk_configuration_issues/</guid>
      <description>Troubleshoot UAN Disk Configuration Issues Perform this procedure to enable uan_disk_config to run successfully by erasing existing disk partitions. UAN disk configuration will fail if the disk on the node is already partitioned. Manually erase any existing partitions to fix the issue.
This procedure currently only addresses uan_disk_config errors due to existing disk partitions.
Refer to About UAN Configuration for an explanation of UAN disk configuration.
The most common cause of failure in the uan_disk_config role is the disk having been previously configured without a /scratch and /swap partition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/upgrade/notable_changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 14:14:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/upgrade/notable_changes/</guid>
      <description>Notable Changes The following guide describes changes included in a particular UAN version that may be of note during an install or upgrade.
When an upgrade is being performed, please review the notable changes for all of the UAN versions up to the version being installed. If a particular version does not appear in this guide, it may have only had minor changes. For a full account of the changes involved in a release, consult the ChangeLog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/upgrade/upgrades/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 14:14:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/upgrade/upgrades/</guid>
      <description>Upgrades Performing an upgrade of UAN from one version to the next follows the same general process as a fresh install. Some considerations may need to be made when merging the existing CFS configuration with the latest CFS configuration provided by the release.
The overall workflow for completing a UAN upgrade involves:
Perform the UAN Installation
Review any Notable Changes
Merge UAN CFS Configuration Data
Create UAN images and reboot</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/test-plan/test-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 14:14:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/test-plan/test-plan/</guid>
      <description>Test Plan for User Access Node (UAN) and Repurposed Compute Node as UAN The following is the test plan for the User Access Node (UAN) or a Compute Node that has been repurposed to function as a UAN. The tests are grouped in three categories:
Unit tests Integration tests Functional tests Unit Tests When possible, unit tests are run when the various components of UAN are built (uan-rpms, uan, and uan-product-stream).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/install/install_the_uan_product_stream/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 14:14:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-260-alpha6/install/install_the_uan_product_stream/</guid>
      <description>Install or Upgrade UAN Install and Upgrade Framework The Install and Upgrade Framework (IUF) provides commands which install, upgrade and deploy products on systems managed by CSM. IUF capabilities are described in detail in the IUF section of the Cray System Management Documentation. The initial install and upgrade workflows described in the HPE Cray EX System Software Stack Installation and Upgrade Guide for CSM (S-8052) detail when and how to use IUF with a new release of UAN or any other HPE Cray EX product.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
