<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>User Access Node (UAN)</title>
    <link>/docs-uan/en-2511/installation_prereqs/</link>
    <description>Recent content on User Access Node (UAN)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 03:15:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/docs-uan/en-2511/installation_prereqs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-2511/installation_prereqs/prepare_for_uan_product_installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 03:15:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-2511/installation_prereqs/prepare_for_uan_product_installation/</guid>
      <description>Prepare for UAN Product Installation Perform this procedure to ready the HPE Cray EX supercomputer for UAN product installation.
Install and configure the COS product before performing this procedure.
Verify that the management network switches are properly configured.
Refer to the switch configuration procedures in the HPE Cray System Management Documentation.
Ensure that the management network switches have the proper firmware.
Refer to the procedure &amp;ldquo;Update the Management Network Firmware&amp;rdquo; in the HPE Cray EX hardware documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-2511/installation_prereqs/configure_the_bmc_for_uans_with_ilo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 03:15:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-2511/installation_prereqs/configure_the_bmc_for_uans_with_ilo/</guid>
      <description>Configure the BMC for UANs with iLO Perform this procedure to enable the IPMI/DCMI settings on an HPE UAN that are necessary to continue UAN product installation on an HPE Cray EX supercomputer.
Perform the first three steps of Prepare for UAN Product Installation before performing this procedure.
Create the SSH tunnel necessary to access the BMC web GUI interface.
Find the IP or hostname for a UAN.
Create an SSH tunnel to the UAN BMC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-2511/installation_prereqs/configure_the_bios_of_an_hpe_uan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 03:15:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-2511/installation_prereqs/configure_the_bios_of_an_hpe_uan/</guid>
      <description>Configure the BIOS of an HPE UAN Perform this procedure to configure the network interface and boot settings required by HPE UANs.
Before the UAN product can be installed on HPE UANs, specific network interface and boot settings must be configured in the BIOS.
Perform Configure the BMC for UANs with iLO before performing this procedure.
Force a UAN to reboot into the BIOS.
In the following command, UAN_BMC_XNAME is the xname of the BMC of the UAN to configure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-2511/installation_prereqs/configure_the_bios_of_a_gigabyte_uan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 03:15:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-2511/installation_prereqs/configure_the_bios_of_a_gigabyte_uan/</guid>
      <description>Configure the BIOS of a Gigabyte UAN Perform this procedure to configure the network interface and boot settings required by Gigabyte UANs.
Before the UAN product can be installed on Gigabyte UANs, specific network interface and boot settings must be configured in the BIOS.
Press the Delete key to enter the setup utility when prompted to do so in the console.
Navigate to the boot menu.
Set the Boot Option #1 field to Network:UEFI: PXE IP4 Intel(R) I350 Gigabit Network Connection.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
