<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>User Access Node (UAN)</title>
    <link>/docs-uan/en-270/advanced/</link>
    <description>Recent content on User Access Node (UAN)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 03:04:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/docs-uan/en-270/advanced/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-270/advanced/enabling_can_chn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 03:04:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-270/advanced/enabling_can_chn/</guid>
      <description>Enabling the Customer Access Network (CAN) or the Customer High Speed Network (CHN) The UAN product provides a role, uan_interfaces in the Configuration Framework Service (CFS). This role is suitable for Application type nodes, and in some circumstances, configuring the CHN on Compute type nodes.
Enable CAN or CHN by setting the following in the UAN CFS repo (the filename may be modified to whatever is appropriate):
ncn-m001:~/ $ cat group_vars/Application_UAN/can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-270/advanced/repurposing_compute_as_uan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 03:04:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-270/advanced/repurposing_compute_as_uan/</guid>
      <description>Repurposing a Compute Node as a UAN This section describes how to repurpose a compute node to be used as a User Access Node (UAN). This reconfiguration is typically done when the processor type of the compute node is not yet available in a UAN server.
Overview The following steps outline the process of repurposing a compute node to be used as a UAN.
Verify that the System Default Route is set to CHN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-270/advanced/designating_application_nodes_for_k3s/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 03:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-270/advanced/designating_application_nodes_for_k3s/</guid>
      <description>Designating Application Nodes for K3s (Technical Preview) WARNING: This feature is a Technical Preview. Future releases will streamline these manual configuration steps. Therefore, some of these configuration options may change in future releases.
Overview Before K3s can be enabled to support UAIs on Application nodes, the Application nodes must be grouped in HSM as either k3s_server or k3s_agent nodes. The UAN Ansible K3s playbook uses these groups to determine what role they will have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-270/advanced/enabling_k3s/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 03:04:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-270/advanced/enabling_k3s/</guid>
      <description>Configuring a UAN for K3s (Technical Preview) WARNING: This feature is a Technical Preview, as such it requires completion of the Prerequisites section. Future releases will streamline these manual configuration steps and enhance the experience of using the rootless Podman containers. Therefore, some of these configuration options may change in future releases.
UAI Experience on UANs In UAN 2.6, a new playbook has been added to create a single node, K3s cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-270/advanced/sles_image/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 03:04:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-270/advanced/sles_image/</guid>
      <description>Booting an Application Node with a SLE HPC Image (Technical Preview) A SLE HPC image is available for use with Application Node types such as gateways and LNet routers. This image is considered a &amp;ldquo;Technical Preview&amp;rdquo; as the initial support for booting with SLE HPC Images without COS. This Application Node image differs from the standard COS-based image because this image does not include the COS kernel and libraries that Compute Nodes (CNs) have.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
