<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>User Access Node (UAN)</title>
    <link>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/upgrade/</link>
    <description>Recent content on User Access Node (UAN)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 21:34:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/upgrade/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/upgrade/notable_changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 21:34:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/upgrade/notable_changes/</guid>
      <description>Notable Changes The following guide describes changes included in a particular UAN version that may be of note during an install or upgrade.
When an upgrade is being performed, please review the notable changes for all of the UAN versions up to the version being installed. If a particular version does not appear in this guide, it may have only had minor changes. For a full account of the changes involved in a release, consult the ChangeLog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/upgrade/upgrade_uan_software_product/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 21:34:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/upgrade/upgrade_uan_software_product/</guid>
      <description>Upgrade UAN Software Product Follow upgrade instructions in HPE Cray EX System Software Getting Started Guide (S-8000) to upgrade the UAN software product. Those instructions provide:
Complete information about the options and arguments for the cne-install tool The correct sequence for upgrading UAN and other HPE Cray EX software products. If UAN and COS were upgraded at the same time using cne-install, skip these instructions and Boot UANs.
About cne-install The Compute Node Environment (CNE) installer (cne-install) simplifies upgrading several products of the HPE Cray EX software like SLE, COS, Slingshot Host Software, UAN, SMA, and SAT by providing the ability to automate many CNE upgrade tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/upgrade/merge_uan_configuration_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 21:34:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/upgrade/merge_uan_configuration_data/</guid>
      <description>Merge UAN Configuration Data Perform this procedure to update the UAN product configuration.
Before performing this procedure, perform Install the UAN Product Stream
In this procedure, an upgrade from UAN 2.0.0 to UAN 2.3.1 is being performed. Administrators should replace the versions seen in this procedure with the versions being upgraded on the system. Additionally, this guide describes upgrading an integration branch. Each CFS branch responsible for configuring the various types of Application and UANs should be upgraded.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
