<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>User Access Node (UAN)</title>
    <link>/docs-uan/en-2511/advanced/</link>
    <description>Recent content on User Access Node (UAN)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 03:04:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/docs-uan/en-2511/advanced/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-2511/advanced/customizing_uan_images_manually/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 03:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-2511/advanced/customizing_uan_images_manually/</guid>
      <description>Customizing UAN Images Manually Query IMS for the UAN Image you want to customize.
ncn-m001:~/ $ cray ims images list --format json | jq &amp;#39;.[] | select(.name | contains(&amp;#34;uan&amp;#34;))&amp;#39; { &amp;#34;created&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;2021-02-18T17:17:44.168655+00:00&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;id&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;6d46d601-c41f-444d-8b49-c9a2a55d3c21&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;link&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;etag&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;371b62c9f0263e4c8c70c8602ccd5158&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;path&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;s3://boot-images/6d46d601-c41f-444d-8b49-c9a2a55d3c21/manifest.json&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;type&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;s3&amp;#34; }, &amp;#34;name&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;uan-PRODUCT_VERSION-image&amp;#34; } Create a variable for the IMS image id in the returned data.
ncn-m001:~/ $ export IMS_IMAGE_ID=6d46d601-c41f-444d-8b49-c9a2a55d3c21 Using the IMS_IMAGE_ID, follow the instructions in the Customize an Image Root Using IMS in the CSM documentation to build the UAN Image.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-2511/advanced/enabling_can_chn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 03:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-2511/advanced/enabling_can_chn/</guid>
      <description>Enabling the Customer Access Network (CAN) or the Customer High Speed Network (CHN) The UAN product provides a role, uan_interfaces in the Configuration Framework Service (CFS). This role is suitable for Application type nodes, and in some circumstancs, configuring the CHN, on Compute type nodes.
Enable CAN or CHN by setting the following in the UAN CFS repo (the filename may be modified to whatever is appropriate):
ncn-m001:~/ $ cat group_vars/Application_UAN/can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-2511/advanced/repurposing_compute_as_uan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 03:04:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-2511/advanced/repurposing_compute_as_uan/</guid>
      <description>Repurposing a Compute Node as a UAN This section describes how to repurpose a compute node to be used as a User Access Node (UAN). This is typically done when the processor type of the compute node is not yet available in a UAN server.
Overview The following steps outline the process of repurposing a compute node to be used as a UAN.
Verify the System Default Route is set to CHN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-2511/advanced/sles_image/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 03:04:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-2511/advanced/sles_image/</guid>
      <description>Booting an Application Node with a SLES Image (Technical Preview) A SLES image is available for use with Application type nodes. This image is currently considered a &amp;ldquo;Technical Preview&amp;rdquo; as the initial support for booting with SLES Images without COS. This guide documents the procedure to boot and configure the new image as it currently differs from the standard COS-based image process in some ways.
The image is built with the same packer/qemu pipeline as Non-Compute-Node Images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-2511/advanced/enabling_k3s/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 03:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-2511/advanced/enabling_k3s/</guid>
      <description>Configuring a UAN for K3s (Technical Preview) WARNING: This feature is currently a Technical Preview, as such it requires completion of the Prerequisites section. Future releases will streamline these manual configuration steps and enhance the experience of using the rootless podman containers. Therefore, some of these configuration options may change in future releases.
UAI Experience on UANs In UAN 2.6, a new playbook has been added to create a single node, K3s cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
