<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>User Access Node (UAN)</title>
    <link>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/</link>
    <description>Recent content on User Access Node (UAN)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 02:01:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/operations/uan_ansible_roles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 02:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/operations/uan_ansible_roles/</guid>
      <description>UAN Ansible Roles uan_disk_config The uan_disk_config role configures swap and scratch disk partitions on UAN nodes.
Requirements There must be disk devices found on the UAN node by the device_filter module or this role will exit with failure. This condition can be ignored by setting uan_require_disk to false. See variable definitions below.
See the library/device_filter.py file for more information on this module.
The device that is found will be unmounted if mounted and a swap partition will be created on the first half of the disk, and a scratch partition on the second half.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/install/install_the_uan_product_stream/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 02:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/install/install_the_uan_product_stream/</guid>
      <description>Install the UAN Product Stream This procedure installs the User Access Nodes (UAN) product on a system so that UAN boot images can be created.
Before performing this procedure:
Initialize and configure the Cray command line interface (CLI) tool. See &amp;ldquo;Configure the Cray Command Line Interface (CLI)&amp;rdquo; in the CSM documentation for more information. Perform Prepare for UAN Product Installation Replace PRODUCT_VERSION in the example commands with the UAN product stream string (2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/advanced/customizing_uan_images_manually/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/advanced/customizing_uan_images_manually/</guid>
      <description>toc_title=customizing uan images manually; given_title=customizing uan images manually; menuTitle: &amp;ldquo;Customizing UAN Images Manually&amp;rdquo; date: Sun Mar 26 02:00:55 UTC 2023 draft: false weight: 51 Customizing UAN Images Manually Query IMS for the UAN Image you want to customize.
ncn-m001:~/ $ cray ims images list --format json | jq &amp;#39;.[] | select(.name | contains(&amp;#34;uan&amp;#34;))&amp;#39; { &amp;#34;created&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;2021-02-18T17:17:44.168655+00:00&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;id&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;6d46d601-c41f-444d-8b49-c9a2a55d3c21&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;link&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;etag&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;371b62c9f0263e4c8c70c8602ccd5158&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;path&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;s3://boot-images/6d46d601-c41f-444d-8b49-c9a2a55d3c21/manifest.json&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;type&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;s3&amp;#34; }, &amp;#34;name&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;uan-PRODUCT_VERSION-image&amp;#34; } Create a variable for the IMS image id in the returned data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/advanced/enabling_can_chn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/advanced/enabling_can_chn/</guid>
      <description>toc_title=enabling the customer access network (can) or the customer high speed network (chn); given_title=enabling the customer access network (can) or the customer high speed network (chn); menuTitle: &amp;ldquo;Enabling the Customer Access Network (CAN) or the Customer High Speed Network (CHN)&amp;rdquo; date: Sun Mar 26 02:00:55 UTC 2023 draft: false weight: 52 Enabling the Customer Access Network (CAN) or the Customer High Speed Network (CHN) The UAN product provides a role, uan_interfaces in the Configuration Framework Service (CFS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/advanced/enabling_k3s/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/advanced/enabling_k3s/</guid>
      <description>toc_title=configuring a uan for k3s (technical preview); given_title=configuring a uan for k3s (technical preview); menuTitle: &amp;ldquo;Configuring a UAN for K3s (Technical Preview)&amp;rdquo; date: Sun Mar 26 02:00:55 UTC 2023 draft: false weight: 55 Configuring a UAN for K3s (Technical Preview) WARNING: This feature is currently a Technical Preview, as such it requires completion of the Prerequisites section. Future releases will streamline these manual configuration steps and enhance the experience of using the rootless podman containers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/advanced/repurposing_compute_as_uan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/advanced/repurposing_compute_as_uan/</guid>
      <description>toc_title=repurposing a compute node as a uan; given_title=repurposing a compute node as a uan; menuTitle: &amp;ldquo;Repurposing a Compute Node as a UAN&amp;rdquo; date: Sun Mar 26 02:00:56 UTC 2023 draft: false weight: 53 Repurposing a Compute Node as a UAN This section describes how to repurpose a compute node to be used as a User Access Node (UAN). This is typically done when the processor type of the compute node is not yet available in a UAN server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/advanced/sles_image/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/advanced/sles_image/</guid>
      <description>toc_title=booting an application node with a sles image (technical preview); given_title=booting an application node with a sles image (technical preview); menuTitle: &amp;ldquo;Booting an Application Node with a SLES Image (Technical Preview)&amp;rdquo; date: Sun Mar 26 02:00:56 UTC 2023 draft: false weight: 54 Booting an Application Node with a SLES Image (Technical Preview) A SLES image is available for use with Application type nodes. This image is currently considered a &amp;ldquo;Technical Preview&amp;rdquo; as the initial support for booting with SLES Images without COS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/installation_prereqs/configure_the_bios_of_a_gigabyte_uan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/installation_prereqs/configure_the_bios_of_a_gigabyte_uan/</guid>
      <description>toc_title=configure the bios of a gigabyte uan; given_title=configure the bios of a gigabyte uan; menuTitle: &amp;ldquo;Configure the BIOS of a Gigabyte UAN&amp;rdquo; date: Sun Mar 26 02:00:57 UTC 2023 draft: false weight: 24 Configure the BIOS of a Gigabyte UAN Perform this procedure to configure the network interface and boot settings required by Gigabyte UANs.
Before the UAN product can be installed on Gigabyte UANs, specific network interface and boot settings must be configured in the BIOS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/installation_prereqs/configure_the_bios_of_an_hpe_uan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/installation_prereqs/configure_the_bios_of_an_hpe_uan/</guid>
      <description>toc_title=configure the bios of an hpe uan; given_title=configure the bios of an hpe uan; menuTitle: &amp;ldquo;Configure the BIOS of an HPE UAN&amp;rdquo; date: Sun Mar 26 02:00:57 UTC 2023 draft: false weight: 23 Configure the BIOS of an HPE UAN Perform this procedure to configure the network interface and boot settings required by HPE UANs.
Before the UAN product can be installed on HPE UANs, specific network interface and boot settings must be configured in the BIOS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/installation_prereqs/configure_the_bmc_for_uans_with_ilo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/installation_prereqs/configure_the_bmc_for_uans_with_ilo/</guid>
      <description>toc_title=configure the bmc for uans with ilo; given_title=configure the bmc for uans with ilo; menuTitle: &amp;ldquo;Configure the BMC for UANs with iLO&amp;rdquo; date: Sun Mar 26 02:00:57 UTC 2023 draft: false weight: 22 Configure the BMC for UANs with iLO Perform this procedure to enable the IPMI/DCMI settings on an HPE UAN that are necessary to continue UAN product installation on an HPE Cray EX supercomputer.
Perform the first three steps of Prepare for UAN Product Installation before performing this procedure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/installation_prereqs/prepare_for_uan_product_installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/installation_prereqs/prepare_for_uan_product_installation/</guid>
      <description>toc_title=prepare for uan product installation; given_title=prepare for uan product installation; menuTitle: &amp;ldquo;Prepare for UAN Product Installation&amp;rdquo; date: Sun Mar 26 02:00:57 UTC 2023 draft: false weight: 21 Prepare for UAN Product Installation Perform this procedure to ready the HPE Cray EX supercomputer for UAN product installation.
Install and configure the COS product before performing this procedure.
Verify that the management network switches are properly configured.
Refer to the switch configuration procedures in the HPE Cray System Management Documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/operations/about_uan_configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/operations/about_uan_configuration/</guid>
      <description>toc_title=about uan configuration; given_title=about uan configuration; menuTitle: &amp;ldquo;About UAN Configuration&amp;rdquo; date: Sun Mar 26 02:00:57 UTC 2023 draft: false weight: 41 About UAN Configuration This section describes the Ansible playbooks and roles that configure UANs.
UAN configuration overview Configuration of UAN nodes is performed by the Configuration Framework Service (CFS). CFS can apply configuration to both images and nodes. When the configuration is applied to nodes, the nodes must be booted and accessible through SSH over the Node Management Network (NMN).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/operations/boot_uans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/operations/boot_uans/</guid>
      <description>toc_title=boot uans; given_title=boot uans; menuTitle: &amp;ldquo;Boot UANs&amp;rdquo; date: Sun Mar 26 02:00:58 UTC 2023 draft: false weight: 48 Boot UANs Perform this procedure to boot UANs using BOS so that they are ready for user logins.
Perform Create UAN Boot Images before performing this procedure.
Create a BOS session to boot the UAN nodes. Replace uan-sessiontemplate-PRODUCT_VERSION in the following command with the ID of the session template created by the initial UAN product installation or the UAN product upgrade process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/operations/build_a_new_uan_image_using_the_cos_recipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/operations/build_a_new_uan_image_using_the_cos_recipe/</guid>
      <description>toc_title=build a new uan image using a cos recipe; given_title=build a new uan image using a cos recipe; menuTitle: &amp;ldquo;Build a New UAN Image Using a COS Recipe&amp;rdquo; date: Sun Mar 26 02:00:58 UTC 2023 draft: false weight: 42 Build a New UAN Image Using a COS Recipe Prior to UAN 2.3, a similar copy of the COS recipe was imported with the UAN install. In the UAN 2.3 release, UAN does not install a recipe, and a COS recipe must be used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/operations/configure_interfaces_on_uans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/operations/configure_interfaces_on_uans/</guid>
      <description>toc_title=configure interfaces on uans; given_title=configure interfaces on uans; menuTitle: &amp;ldquo;Configure Interfaces on UANs&amp;rdquo; date: Sun Mar 26 02:00:58 UTC 2023 draft: false weight: 45 Configure Interfaces on UANs Perform this procedure to set network interfaces on UANs by editing a configuration file.
Interface configuration is performed by the uan_interfaces Ansible role. For details on the variables referred to in this procedure, see UAN Ansible Roles.
In the command examples in this procedure, PRODUCT_VERSION refers to the current installed version of the UAN product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/operations/configure_pluggable_authentication_modules_pam_on_uans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/operations/configure_pluggable_authentication_modules_pam_on_uans/</guid>
      <description>toc_title=configure pluggable authentication modules (pam) on uans; given_title=configure pluggable authentication modules (pam) on uans; menuTitle: &amp;ldquo;Configure Pluggable Authentication Modules (PAM) on UANs&amp;rdquo; date: Sun Mar 26 02:00:58 UTC 2023 draft: false weight: 46 Configure Pluggable Authentication Modules (PAM) on UANs Perform this procedure to configure PAM on UANs. This enables dynamic authentication support for system services.
Intialize and configure the Cray command line interface (CLI) tool on the system. See &amp;ldquo;Configure the Cray Command Line Interface (CLI)&amp;rdquo; in the CSM documentation for more information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/operations/create_uan_boot_images/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/operations/create_uan_boot_images/</guid>
      <description>toc_title=create uan boot images; given_title=create uan boot images; menuTitle: &amp;ldquo;Create UAN Boot Images&amp;rdquo; date: Sun Mar 26 02:00:58 UTC 2023 draft: false weight: 43 Create UAN Boot Images This procedure updates the configuration management git repository to match the installed version of the UAN product. That updated configuration is then used to create UAN boot images and a BOS session template.
UAN specific configuration, and other required configurations related to UANs are covered in this topic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/operations/mount_a_new_file_system_on_an_uan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/operations/mount_a_new_file_system_on_an_uan/</guid>
      <description>toc_title=mount a new file system on a uan; given_title=mount a new file system on a uan; menuTitle: &amp;ldquo;Mount a New File System on a UAN&amp;rdquo; date: Sun Mar 26 02:00:58 UTC 2023 draft: false weight: 44 Mount a New File System on a UAN Perform this procedure to create a mount point for a new file system on a UAN.
Perform Steps 1-9 of Create UAN Boot Images.
Create a directory for Application role nodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/test-plan/k3s_test_plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/test-plan/k3s_test_plan/</guid>
      <description>toc_title=test plan for uais on uans (k3s verification); given_title=test plan for uais on uans (k3s verification); menuTitle: &amp;ldquo;Test Plan for UAIs on UANs (K3s Verification)&amp;rdquo; date: Sun Mar 26 02:00:59 UTC 2023 draft: false weight: 82 Test Plan for UAIs on UANs (K3s Verification) Overview Perform this procedure to verify that K3s on UANs can launch the services necessary to replicate UAIs as Podman containers.
The steps in this guide are biased towards simplicity and light on explanation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/test-plan/test-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/test-plan/test-plan/</guid>
      <description>toc_title=test plan for user access node (uan) and repurposed compute node as uan; given_title=test plan for user access node (uan) and repurposed compute node as uan; menuTitle: &amp;ldquo;Test Plan for User Access Node (UAN) and Repurposed Compute Node as UAN&amp;rdquo; date: Sun Mar 26 02:00:59 UTC 2023 draft: false weight: 81 Test Plan for User Access Node (UAN) and Repurposed Compute Node as UAN The following is the test plan for the User Access Node (UAN) or a Compute Node that has been repurposed to function as a UAN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/troubleshooting/troubleshoot_uan_boot_issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/troubleshooting/troubleshoot_uan_boot_issues/</guid>
      <description>toc_title=troubleshoot uan boot issues; given_title=troubleshoot uan boot issues; menuTitle: &amp;ldquo;Troubleshoot UAN Boot Issues&amp;rdquo; date: Sun Mar 26 02:01:00 UTC 2023 draft: false weight: 71 Troubleshoot UAN Boot Issues The UAN boot process BOS boots UANs. BOS uses session templates to define various parameters such as:
Which nodes to boot Which image to boot Kernel parameters Whether to perform post-boot configuration (Node Personalization) of the nodes by CFS. Which CFS configuration to use if Node Personalization is enabled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/troubleshooting/troubleshoot_uan_cfs_and_network_configuration_issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/troubleshooting/troubleshoot_uan_cfs_and_network_configuration_issues/</guid>
      <description>toc_title=troubleshoot uan cfs and network configuration issues; given_title=troubleshoot uan cfs and network configuration issues; menuTitle: &amp;ldquo;Troubleshoot UAN CFS and Network Configuration Issues&amp;rdquo; date: Sun Mar 26 02:01:00 UTC 2023 draft: false weight: 72 Troubleshoot UAN CFS and Network Configuration Issues Examine the UAN CFS pod logs to help troubleshoot CFS and networking issues on UANs.
Read About UAN Configuration before starting this procedure.
Obtain the name of the CFS session that failed by running the following command on a management or worker NCN:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/troubleshooting/troubleshoot_uan_disk_configuration_issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/troubleshooting/troubleshoot_uan_disk_configuration_issues/</guid>
      <description>toc_title=troubleshoot uan disk configuration issues; given_title=troubleshoot uan disk configuration issues; menuTitle: &amp;ldquo;Troubleshoot UAN Disk Configuration Issues&amp;rdquo; date: Sun Mar 26 02:01:00 UTC 2023 draft: false weight: 73 Troubleshoot UAN Disk Configuration Issues Perform this procedure to enable uan_disk_config to run successfully by erasing existing disk partitions. UAN disk configuration will fail if the disk on the node is already partitioned. Manually erase any existing partitions to fix the issue.
This procedure currently only addresses uan_disk_config errors due to existing disk partitions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/upgrade/merge_uan_configuration_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/upgrade/merge_uan_configuration_data/</guid>
      <description>toc_title=merge uan configuration data; given_title=merge uan configuration data; menuTitle: &amp;ldquo;Merge UAN Configuration Data&amp;rdquo; date: Sun Mar 26 02:01:01 UTC 2023 draft: false weight: 63 Merge UAN Configuration Data Perform this procedure to update the UAN product configuration.
Before performing this procedure, perform Install the UAN Product Stream
In this procedure, an upgrade from UAN 2.0.0 to UAN 2.3.1 is being performed. Administrators should replace the versions seen in this procedure with the versions being upgraded on the system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/upgrade/notable_changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/upgrade/notable_changes/</guid>
      <description>toc_title=notable changes; given_title=notable changes; menuTitle: &amp;ldquo;Notable Changes&amp;rdquo; date: Sun Mar 26 02:01:01 UTC 2023 draft: false weight: 61 Notable Changes The following guide describes changes included in a particular UAN version that may be of note during an install or upgrade.
When an upgrade is being performed, please review the notable changes for all of the UAN versions up to the version being installed. If a particular version does not appear in this guide, it may have only had minor changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/upgrade/upgrade_uan_software_product/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-2510-alpha1/upgrade/upgrade_uan_software_product/</guid>
      <description>toc_title=upgrade uan software product; given_title=upgrade uan software product; menuTitle: &amp;ldquo;Upgrade UAN Software Product&amp;rdquo; date: Sun Mar 26 02:01:01 UTC 2023 draft: false weight: 62 Upgrade UAN Software Product Follow upgrade instructions in HPE Cray EX System Software Getting Started Guide (S-8000) to upgrade the UAN software product. Those instructions provide:
Complete information about the options and arguments for the cne-install tool The correct sequence for upgrading UAN and other HPE Cray EX software products.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
