<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>User Access Node (UAN)</title>
    <link>/docs-uan/en-273/</link>
    <description>Recent content on User Access Node (UAN)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 03:04:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/docs-uan/en-273/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-273/installation_prereqs/prepare_for_uan_product_installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 03:04:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-273/installation_prereqs/prepare_for_uan_product_installation/</guid>
      <description>Prepare for UAN Product Installation Perform this procedure to ready the HPE Cray Supercomputing EX system for HPE Cray Supercomputing UAN product installation.
Install and configure the HPE Cray Supercomputing COS product before performing this procedure.
If the HPE Cray Supercomputing EX system contains Compute Nodes (CNs) that will be repurposed as UANs, those CNs must be configured as CNs first. The HPE Cray Supercomputing User Access Node (UAN) Administrator Guide (S-8033) provides instructions for reconfiguring a CN as UAN after product installation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-273/installation_prereqs/configure_the_bmc_for_uans_with_ilo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 03:04:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-273/installation_prereqs/configure_the_bmc_for_uans_with_ilo/</guid>
      <description>Configure the BMC for UANs with iLO Perform this procedure to enable the IPMI/DCMI settings on an HPE UAN that are necessary to continue HPE Cray Supercomputing UAN product installation on an HPE Supercomputing Cray EX system.
Perform the first three steps of Prepare for UAN Product Installation before performing this procedure.
Create the SSH tunnel necessary to access the BMC web GUI interface.
Find the IP or hostname for a UAN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-273/installation_prereqs/configure_the_bios_of_an_hpe_uan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 03:04:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-273/installation_prereqs/configure_the_bios_of_an_hpe_uan/</guid>
      <description>Configure the BIOS of an HPE UAN Perform this procedure to configure the network interface and boot settings required by HPE UANs.
Before the HPE Cray Supercomputing UAN product can be installed on HPE UANs, specific network interface and boot settings must be configured in the BIOS.
Perform Configure the BMC for UANs with iLO before performing this procedure.
Force a UAN to reboot into the BIOS.
In the following command, UAN_BMC_XNAME is the xname of the BMC of the UAN to configure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-273/operations/basic_uan_configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 03:04:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-273/operations/basic_uan_configuration/</guid>
      <description>Basic UAN Configuration UAN configuration overview The Configuration Framework Service (CFS) performs the configuration of UAN nodes. CFS can apply configuration to both images and nodes. When the configuration is applied to nodes, the nodes must be booted and accessible through SSH over the Node Management Network (NMN).
The preferred method of creating CFS configurations is to use the Shasta Admin Toolkit (SAT) sat bootprep command. This command automates the manual process described in Create UAN Boot Images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-273/operations/build_a_new_uan_image_using_the_cos_recipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 03:04:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-273/operations/build_a_new_uan_image_using_the_cos_recipe/</guid>
      <description>Build a New UAN Image Using a COS Recipe Prior to HPE Cray Supercomputing UAN release 2.3, a similar copy of the COS image recipe was imported with the UAN install. Beginning with the 2.3 release, this product does not install an image recipe. A COS image recipe must be used. Additional UAN packages will be installed by CFS and the uan_packages role. In UAN release 2.6, this procedure is automated as part of the IUF process of installing and upgrading the UAN product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-273/operations/create_uan_boot_images/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 03:04:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-273/operations/create_uan_boot_images/</guid>
      <description>Create UAN Boot Images Beginning with UAN 2.6, the procedures described here are automatically performed by IUF during installation and upgrade of the HPE Cray Supercomputing UAN product. See Install or Upgrade UAN for details. The procedures shown here are for cases when a new image is needed after the UAN product is installed or upgraded and the product release is prior to 2.6. For release 2.6 and newer, perform Build a New UAN Image Using a COS Recipe for these cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-273/operations/mount_a_new_file_system_on_an_uan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 03:04:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-273/operations/mount_a_new_file_system_on_an_uan/</guid>
      <description>Mount a New File System on a UAN Perform this procedure to create a mount point for a new file system on a UAN.
Perform Steps 1-9 of Create UAN Boot Images.
Create a directory for Application role nodes.
ncn-w001# mkdir -p group_vars/Application Define the home directory information for the new file system in the filesystems.yml file.
ncn-w001# vi group_vars/Application/filesystems.yml --- filesystems: - src: 10.252.1.1:/home mount_point: /home fstype: nfs4 opts: rw,noauto state: mounted Add the change from the working directory to the staging area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-273/operations/configure_interfaces_on_uans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 03:04:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-273/operations/configure_interfaces_on_uans/</guid>
      <description>Configure Interfaces on UANs Perform this procedure to configure network interfaces on UANs by editing a configuration file.
The uan_interfaces Ansible role performs interface configuration. For details on the variables used in this procedure, see uan_interfaces.
In the command examples of this procedure, PRODUCT_VERSION refers to the current installed version of the HPE Cray Supercomputing UAN product. Replace PRODUCT_VERSION with the product version number string when executing the commands.
Node Management Networking By default, the Node Management Network (NMN) is connected to a single nmn0 interface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-273/operations/configure_pluggable_authentication_modules_pam_on_uans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 03:04:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-273/operations/configure_pluggable_authentication_modules_pam_on_uans/</guid>
      <description>Configure Pluggable Authentication Modules (PAM) on UANs Perform this procedure to configure PAM on UANs. PAM enables dynamic authentication support for system services.
Initialize and configure the Cray CLI tool on the system. See &amp;ldquo;Configure the Cray Command Line Interface (CLI)&amp;rdquo; in the CSM documentation for more information.
Verify that the Gitea Version Control Service (VCS) is running.
ncn-m001# kubectl get pods --all-namespaces | grep vcs services gitea-vcs-f57c54c4f-j8k4t 2/2 Running 1 11d services gitea-vcs-postgres-0 2/2 Running 0 11d Retrieve the initial Gitea login credentials for the crayvcs user name.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-273/operations/boot_uans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 03:04:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-273/operations/boot_uans/</guid>
      <description>Boot UANs Perform this procedure to boot UANs using BOS so that they are ready for user logins.
Prerequisites IUF is not being used to automate this process Create UAN Boot Images Procedure Create a BOS session to boot the UAN nodes. Replace uan-sessiontemplate-PRODUCT_VERSION in the following command with the ID of the session template created by the initial HPE Cray Supercomputing UAN product installation or the UAN product upgrade process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-273/operations/cve-2023-0461/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 03:04:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-273/operations/cve-2023-0461/</guid>
      <description>Mitigation for CVE-2023-0461 Description There is a use-after-free vulnerability in the Linux Kernel which can be exploited to achieve local privilege escalation. To reach the vulnerability kernel configuration flag CONFIG_TLS or CONFIG_XFRM_ESPINTCP has to be configured, but the operation does not require any privilege. There is a use-after-free bug of icsk_ulp_data of a struct inet_connection_sock. When CONFIG_TLS is enabled, a user can install a TLS context (struct tls_context) on a connected TCP socket.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-273/advanced/enabling_can_chn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 03:04:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-273/advanced/enabling_can_chn/</guid>
      <description>Enabling the Customer Access Network (CAN) or the Customer High Speed Network (CHN) The HPE Cray Supercomputing UAN product provides a role, uan_interfaces in the Configuration Framework Service (CFS). This role is suitable for Application type nodes, and in some circumstances, configuring the CHN on Compute type nodes.
Enable CAN or CHN by setting the following in the UAN CFS repo (the filename may be modified to whatever is appropriate):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-273/advanced/repurposing_compute_as_uan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 03:04:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-273/advanced/repurposing_compute_as_uan/</guid>
      <description>Repurposing a Compute Node as a UAN This section describes how to repurpose a compute node to be used as a User Access Node (UAN). This reconfiguration is typically done when the processor type of the compute node is not yet available in a UAN server.
Overview The following steps outline the process of repurposing a compute node to be used as a UAN.
Verify that the System Default Route is set to CHN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-273/advanced/designating_application_nodes_for_k3s/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 03:04:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-273/advanced/designating_application_nodes_for_k3s/</guid>
      <description>Designating Application Nodes for K3s (Technical Preview) WARNING: This feature is a Technical Preview. Future releases will streamline these manual configuration steps. Therefore, some of these configuration options may change in future releases.
Prerequisites The node or nodes that will run K3s must have a local disk because Podman requires it. Overview Before K3s can be enabled to support UAIs on Application nodes, the Application nodes must be grouped in HSM as either k3s_server or k3s_agent nodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-273/advanced/enabling_k3s/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 03:04:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-273/advanced/enabling_k3s/</guid>
      <description>Configuring a UAN for K3s (Technical Preview) WARNING: This feature is a Technical Preview, as such it requires completion of the Prerequisites section. Future releases will streamline these manual configuration steps and enhance the experience of using the rootless Podman containers. Therefore, some of these configuration options may change in future releases.
UAI Experience on UANs In HPE Cray Supercomputing UAN release 2.6, a new playbook has been added to create a single node, K3s cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-273/upgrade/notable_changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 03:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-273/upgrade/notable_changes/</guid>
      <description>Notable Changes The following guide describes changes included in a particular UAN version that may be of note during an install or upgrade.
When an upgrade is being performed, review the notable changes for all the UAN versions up to the version being installed. If a particular version does not appear in this guide, it may have only had minor changes. For a full account of the changes involved in a release, consult the ChangeLog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-273/troubleshooting/troubleshoot_uan_boot_issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 03:04:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-273/troubleshooting/troubleshoot_uan_boot_issues/</guid>
      <description>Troubleshoot UAN Boot Issues The UAN boot process BOS boots UANs. BOS uses session templates to define various parameters such as:
Which nodes to boot Which image to boot Kernel parameters Whether to perform post-boot configuration (Node Personalization) of the nodes by CFS. Which CFS configuration to use if Node Personalization is enabled. UAN boots are performed in three phases:
PXE booting an iPXE binary that will load the initrd of the UAN image that will boot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-273/troubleshooting/troubleshoot_uan_cfs_and_network_configuration_issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 03:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-273/troubleshooting/troubleshoot_uan_cfs_and_network_configuration_issues/</guid>
      <description>Troubleshoot UAN CFS and Network Configuration Issues Examine the UAN CFS pod logs to help troubleshoot CFS and networking issues on UANs.
Read Basic UAN Configuration before starting this procedure.
Obtain the name of the CFS session that failed by running the following command on a management or worker NCN:
This example sorts the list of CFS sessions so that the most recent one is at the bottom.
ncn# kubectl -n services get pods --sort-by=.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-273/troubleshooting/troubleshoot_uan_disk_configuration_issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 03:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-273/troubleshooting/troubleshoot_uan_disk_configuration_issues/</guid>
      <description>Troubleshoot UAN Disk Configuration Issues Perform this procedure to enable uan_disk_config to run successfully by erasing existing disk partitions. UAN disk configuration will fail if the disk on the node is already partitioned. Manually erase any existing partitions to fix the issue.
This procedure currently only addresses uan_disk_config errors due to existing disk partitions.
See Basic UAN Configuration for an explanation of UAN disk configuration.
The most common cause of failure in the uan_disk_config role is the disk having been previously configured without a /scratch and /swap partition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-273/test-plan/test-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 03:04:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-273/test-plan/test-plan/</guid>
      <description>Test Plan for User Access Node (UAN) and Repurposed Compute Node as UAN The following is the test plan for the User Access Node (UAN) or a Compute Node that has been repurposed to function as a UAN. The tests are grouped in three categories:
Unit tests Integration tests Functional tests Unit Tests When possible, unit tests are run when the various components of UAN are built (uan-rpms, uan, and uan-product-stream).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-273/upgrade/upgrades/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 03:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-273/upgrade/upgrades/</guid>
      <description>Upgrades Performing an upgrade of the HPE Cray Supercomputing UAN product from one version to the next follows the same general process as a fresh install. Some considerations may need to be made when merging the existing CFS configuration with the latest CFS configuration provided by the release.
The overall workflow for completing a UAN upgrade involves:
Perform the UAN Installation
Review any Notable Changes
Merge UAN CFS Configuration Data</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-273/operations/uan_shadow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 03:04:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-273/operations/uan_shadow/</guid>
      <description>uan_shadow The uan_shadow role configures the root password on UAN nodes.
Requirements The root password hash has to be installed in HashiCorp Vault at secret/uan root_password.
Role Variables Available variables are in the following list, including default values (see defaults/main.yml):
uan_vault_url The URL for the HashiCorp Vault
Example:
uan_vault_url: &amp;#34;http://cray-vault.vault:8200&amp;#34; uan_vault_role_file The required Kubernetes role file for HashiCorp Vault access.
Example:
uan_vault_role_file: /var/run/secrets/kubernetes.io/serviceaccount/namespace uan_vault_jwt_file The path to the required Kubernetes token file for HashiCorp Vault access.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-273/operations/uan_interfaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 03:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-273/operations/uan_interfaces/</guid>
      <description>uan_interfaces The uan_interfaces role configures site or customer-defined network interfaces and Customer Access Network (CAN) network interfaces on UAN nodes.
Requirements None.
Role Variables Available variables are in the following list, including default values (see defaults/main.yml):
uan_nmn_bond A Boolean variable controlling the configuration of the Node Management Network (NMN). When true, the NMN network connection will be configured as a bonded pair of interfaces defined by the members of the uan_nmn_bond_slaves variable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-273/operations/uan_ldap/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 03:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-273/operations/uan_ldap/</guid>
      <description>uan_ldap The uan_ldap role configures LDAP and AD groups on UAN nodes.
Requirements NSCD, pam-config, sssd.
Role Variables Available variables are in the following list, including default values (see defaults/main.yml):
uan_ldap_setup A Boolean variable to selectively skip the setup of LDAP on nodes it would otherwise be configured due to uan_ldap_config being defined. The default setting is to setup LDAP when uan_ldap_config is not empty.
Example:
uan_ldap_setup: yes uan_ldap_config Configures LDAP domains and servers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-273/operations/uan_motd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 03:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-273/operations/uan_motd/</guid>
      <description>uan_motd The uan_motd role appends text to the /etc/motd file.
Requirements None.
Role Variables Available variables are in the following list, including default values (see defaults/main.yml):
uan_motd_content: [] uan_motd_content Contains text to be added to the end of the /etc/motd file.
Dependencies None.
Example Playbook - hosts: Application_UAN roles: - { role: uan_motd, uan_motd_content: &amp;#34;MOTD CONTENT&amp;#34; } This role is included in the UAN site.yml play.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-273/operations/uan_packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 03:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-273/operations/uan_packages/</guid>
      <description>uan_packages The uan_packages role adds or removes additional repositories and RPMs on UANs using the Ansible zypper_repository and zypper module.
Repositories and packages added to this role will be installed or removed during image customization. Installing RPMs during post-boot node configuration can cause high system loads on large systems so these tasks run only during image customizations.
This role will only run on SLES-based nodes.
Requirements Zypper must be installed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-273/operations/uan_disk_config/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 03:04:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-273/operations/uan_disk_config/</guid>
      <description>uan_disk_config The uan_disk_config role configures swap and scratch disk partitions on UAN nodes.
Requirements There must be disk devices found on the UAN node by the device_filter module or this role will exit with failure. This condition can be ignored by setting uan_require_disk to false. See the following list for variable definitions.
See the library/device_filter.py file for more information on this module.
The device that is found will be unmounted if mounted and a swap partition will be created on the first half of the disk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-273/operations/uan_gpg_keys/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 03:04:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-273/operations/uan_gpg_keys/</guid>
      <description>uan_gpg_keys The uan_gpg_keys role installs the CSM GPG signing public key. This role is a dependency of the uan_packages role.
Requirements The Kubernetes secret must be available in the namespace and field specified by the following uan_gpg_key_* variables. The key must be stored as a base64-encoded string.
Role Variables Available variables are in the following list, including default values (defined in defaults/main.yml):
uan_gpg_key_k8s_secret The Kubernetes secret which contains the GPG public key.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-273/operations/uan_hardening/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 03:04:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-273/operations/uan_hardening/</guid>
      <description>uan_hardening The uan_hardening role configures site or customer-defined network security of UANs, for example preventing SSH access from the UAN over the NMN to NCN nodes.
Requirements None.
Role Variables Available variables are in the following list, including default values (see defaults/main.yml):
disable_ssh_out_nmn_to_management_ncns Boolean variable controlling whether firewall rules are applied at the UAN to prevent SSH outbound over the NMN to the NCN management nodes.
The default value of disable_ssh_out_nmn_to_management_ncns is yes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-273/operations/uan_ca_cert/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 03:04:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-273/operations/uan_ca_cert/</guid>
      <description>uan_ca_cert The uan_ca_cert role installs a CA certificate onto the system.
Requirements None.
Role Variables None.
Dependencies None.
Example Playbook - hosts: Application roles: - role: uan_ca_cert This role is included in the UAN site.yml play.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-273/advanced/sles_image/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 03:04:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-273/advanced/sles_image/</guid>
      <description>Booting an Application Node with a SLE HPC Image (Technical Preview) A SLE HPC image is available for use with Application Node types such as gateways and LNet routers. This image is considered a &amp;ldquo;Technical Preview&amp;rdquo; as the initial support for booting with SLE HPC Images without COS. This Application Node image differs from the standard COS-based image because this image does not include the COS kernel and libraries that Compute Nodes (CNs) have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-uan/en-273/install/install_the_uan_product_stream/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 03:04:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-uan/en-273/install/install_the_uan_product_stream/</guid>
      <description>Install or Upgrade UAN Install and Upgrade Framework The Install and Upgrade Framework (IUF) provides commands which install, upgrade, and deploy products on systems managed by CSM. IUF capabilities are described in detail in the IUF section of the Cray System Management Documentation. The initial install and upgrade workflows described in the HPE Cray EX System Software Stack Installation and Upgrade Guide for CSM (S-8052) detail when and how to use IUF with a new release of UAN or any other HPE Cray EX product.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
